[
  {
    "id": "a0001",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Bacteria in the rumen which synthesis CLA",
    "correctAnswer": "Anaerobic bacteria Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens",
    "optionValues": [
      "Rumen aerobic bacteria Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens",
      "Aerobic bacteria Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens",
      "Anaerobic bacteria Butyrivibrio fibrisolvens",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0002",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "An algae which is source of omega 3 fatty acids",
    "correctAnswer": "Gyptherodinium Cohnis",
    "optionValues": [
      "Schizochytrium species",
      "Gyptherodinium Cohnis",
      "Both 1+2",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0003",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Recommended ratio of n-6:n-3 ratio in diet",
    "correctAnswer": "1∕1",
    "optionValues": [
      "4∕1",
      "1∕1",
      "3∕1",
      "2∕1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0004",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Most common isomer of CLA found in dairy products",
    "correctAnswer": "cis-9, trans -11 CLA",
    "optionValues": [
      "cis-9, trans -11 CLA",
      "trans-10, cis-12 CLA",
      "cis-9, trans -11 CLS",
      "None"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0005",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Omega 3 fatty acid found in animal foods",
    "correctAnswer": "EPA",
    "optionValues": [
      "DHA",
      "EPA",
      "Both",
      "None"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0006",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Pre-dominant n-3 fatty acid present in retina",
    "correctAnswer": "DHA",
    "optionValues": [
      "EPA",
      "Xanthophylls",
      "Carotenoids",
      "DHA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0007",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Eicosanoid responsible for increased vasodilation on intake of n-3 fatty acid",
    "correctAnswer": "increased PGI2, NO",
    "optionValues": [
      "increased TxA2",
      "increased PGI2, NO",
      "increased tissue plasmogen factor",
      "decreased PG12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0008",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Food source of CLA",
    "correctAnswer": "Dairy products",
    "optionValues": [
      "spinach and carrot",
      "red wine",
      "designer eggs",
      "Dairy products"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0009",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following are source of ALNA",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "flaxseeds, sunflower seeds",
      "soyabean oil,canola oil",
      "walnut, methi seeds, mustard seeds",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0010",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Ceramide is",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "aliphatic amino alcohol sphingosine and fatty acid",
      "sphingosine and a fatty acid",
      "Sphingolipids",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0011",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Sphingomyelin is hydrolysed",
    "correctAnswer": "1 and 2",
    "optionValues": [
      "hydrolysed in intestinal lumen",
      "alkaline sphingomyelinase",
      "In presence of pancreatic juice",
      "1 and 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0012",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "which of the following is fat based fat replacers",
    "correctAnswer": "Olestra",
    "optionValues": [
      "Olestra",
      "Polyols",
      "Nu-trim",
      "Simplene"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0013",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Best known ACE inhibitor peptides include",
    "correctAnswer": "Ile-Pro-Pro",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glu-ala-pro",
      "leu-Iso-Val",
      "Ile-Pro-Pro",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0014",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a product with ACE inhibotor peptide",
    "correctAnswer": "Crisco",
    "optionValues": [
      "Calpis",
      "Evolus",
      "Festivo Cheese",
      "Crisco"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0015",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Peptides enhancing mineral absorption",
    "correctAnswer": "Caseinophosphopeptides",
    "optionValues": [
      "Casomrphins",
      "Exorphins",
      "Casoxins",
      "Caseinophosphopeptides"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0016",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "BCAA regulates protein synthesis by",
    "correctAnswer": "1 and 2",
    "optionValues": [
      "increasing vasculature",
      "decreasing expression of atrogenes",
      "decreasing vasculature",
      "1 and 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0017",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Isoflavones increase vasculature to prevent cancer",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0018",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Omega 3 fatty acids are called so because thery have 3 double bonds",
    "correctAnswer": "FALSE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0019",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "An increase in Endothelial derived relaxation factore decreases the blood pressure",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0020",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Isoflavones increase follicular phase and decrease luteal phase of menstrual cycle",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0021",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Omega 3 fatty acids decrease HDL cholesterol levela",
    "correctAnswer": "FALSE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0022",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "BCAA are essential for lymphocyte responsiveness",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0023",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "During endurance exercise BCAA",
    "correctAnswer": "all the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "increases serotonin and fatigue",
      "decreases tryptophan transport to brain",
      "causes central fatigue syndrome",
      "all the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0024",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Glutamine supplementation has following effect among cancer patients undergoing chemotherpay",
    "correctAnswer": "decreases mucositis",
    "optionValues": [
      "increases cachexia",
      "decreases mucositis",
      "causes body wasting",
      "causes gut injury"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0025",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Stanols are type of phytosterol which lacks double bond in the sterol ring",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0026",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a food source of phytosterol",
    "correctAnswer": "carrot and spinach",
    "optionValues": [
      "wheat germ",
      "peanuts",
      "sesame oil",
      "carrot and spinach"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0027",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Red or purple juices are good source of reserveraterol",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0028",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "phytosterol displaces cholesterol and reduces CHD risk by",
    "correctAnswer": "competition for micelle formationand precipitation of cholesterol",
    "optionValues": [
      "does not inhibit cholesterol absorption",
      "increases cholesterol absorption",
      "competition for micelle formationand precipitation of cholesterol",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0029",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "TE of blueberry is 9019",
    "correctAnswer": "quantifies anti oxidant capacity",
    "optionValues": [
      "TE is trolox equivalent",
      "has high antioxidant activity",
      "quantifies anti oxidant capacity",
      "all the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0030",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "flavonols include",
    "correctAnswer": "quercetin, kaemferol, myricetin",
    "optionValues": [
      "catechins",
      "cyanidin",
      "apigenin, luteolin",
      "quercetin, kaemferol, myricetin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0031",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "retina has highest concentration of",
    "correctAnswer": "lutein and zeaxanthin",
    "optionValues": [
      "carotenoids",
      "beta caroten",
      "anthocyanidins",
      "lutein and zeaxanthin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0032",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "higher the intakes of lutein and zeaxanthin",
    "correctAnswer": "lower the risk of ARMD",
    "optionValues": [
      "lower the risk of cancer",
      "lower the risk of ARMD",
      "increases CVD Risk",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0033",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "oats contain soluble fiber",
    "correctAnswer": "beta glucan which is hypoglycemic and hypo cholesterolemic",
    "optionValues": [
      "contains insoluble fiber which relieves constipation",
      "contains both soluble and insoluble fiber",
      "Has no effect",
      "beta glucan which is hypoglycemic and hypo cholesterolemic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0034",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "GLYCONE contains",
    "correctAnswer": "sugar molecule attached",
    "optionValues": [
      "sugar molecule attached",
      "sugar molecule is absent",
      "is hydrolysed by an enzyme before absorption",
      "none of the above",
      "1 and 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0035",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "A commercial source of phytosterol",
    "correctAnswer": "benecol spread",
    "optionValues": [
      "corn oil",
      "olive oil",
      "pumpkin seeds and walnuts",
      "benecol spread"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0036",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "2 classes of phytosterols",
    "correctAnswer": "sterols and stanols",
    "optionValues": [
      "sitosterols and compesterol",
      "sterols and stanols",
      "stanols and sitosterols",
      "campesterol and stigmasterol"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0037",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "High fish intake/ DHA supplementation increases DHA in human milk",
    "correctAnswer": "true",
    "optionValues": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0038",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "correct ration for choice of oil-groundnut oil and soy oil",
    "correctAnswer": "4:1",
    "optionValues": [
      "2:1",
      "4:1",
      "1:3",
      "3:1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0039",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "limitations of fat -based replacer include",
    "correctAnswer": "diarrhoea and cramping, fat soluble vitamins are not absorbed",
    "optionValues": [
      "has no side effects",
      "decreases absorption of fat souble vitamins",
      "diarrhoea and cramping, fat soluble vitamins are not absorbed",
      "only causes diarrhoea and cramping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0040",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "which is not a EPA, DHA supplemented functional foods",
    "correctAnswer": "ultrabake",
    "optionValues": [
      "ultrabake",
      "suguna eggs",
      "junior horlicks",
      "silk soymilk"
    ]
  }
]